Guide to the Political Miscellany
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
[Political miscellany; letters, memoranda, deeds, speeches, accounts, and legal notes]
1640-1660
OSBORN FB200
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
0.03
(1 volume)
Anonymous MS collection.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
For provenance information, consult the appropriate curator.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Scope and Contents
The following finding aid is a complete inventory of the contents of Osborn fb200. This list was reformatted from previously existing cataloging.
Deeds -- England; Law -- England; Legal manuscripts; Speeches, addresses, etc., English; Trials -- England; Great Britain -- Politics and government -- 1625-1649; Great Britain -- Politics and government -- 1649-1660; Finch, John, Baron Finch of Fordwich, 1584-1660; Groby, Thomas Grey, Baron of, 1623?-1657; Lindsey, Robert Bertie, Earl of, 1582-1642; Whitlocke, Bulstrode, 1605-1675 or 1676; Winchester, John Paulet, Marquess of, 1598-1675; Great Britain. Parliament
- Osborn fb200
  - FINCH, JOHN FINCH, 1ST BARON, 1584-1660
    - "The Right Honoble the Lo Keeper his Speech to Seriant Littleton and Seriant Foster the 27th of January 1639." (Box 1)
      Scope and Contents
      Contemporary MS copy
  - FINCH, JOHN FINCH, 1ST BARON, 1584-1660
    - "...Speech to all the Judges of England in the Star Chamber 13 February 1639 before their virtuite." (Box 1)
  - [ANONYMOUS]
    - "A note of Acts of Parliament against foraine Jurisdiction.", [n.d.] (Box 1)
      Anonymous MS copy. [17th century].
  - [ANONYMOUS]
    - "A Breviate of certain Acts of Parliament concerning causes of religion.", [n.d.] (Box 1)
      Anonymous MS copy, [17th century].
  - FREEMAN, RALPH
    - [Deed and land title] (Box 1)
      MS copy, [17th century].
  - LINDSEY, ROBERT BERTIE, 1ST EARL OF, 1582-1642
    - ALS to unknown recipient, [1626 Apr 17] (Box 1)
  - BOX, HENRY
    - "A Relation of Henry Box his Case & of his Commitment to ye Goale of Newgate by ye Lord Maior & Court of Alderman.", [n.d.] (Box 1)
      MS copy, [c.1649].
      London.
  - FREDERICK, JOHN
    - "The Case of John Fredericke Concerning ye Anne ffrigot bought of the Comissioner for prize goods at Plymouth ...", [n.d.] (Box 1)
  - GREY, SIR THOMAS GREY, BARON OF GROBY, 1623?-1657
    - [Document appointing Thomas Beale to be Lieutenant and Ranger under Grey, 1646 Sep 4.] (Box 1)
      Contemporary MS copy.
  - [ANONYMOUS]
    - "Reasons for the conitynvance of the Comon assurance of Lands by Fines." (Box 1)
      Anonymous MS copy, [c.17th century].
  - WHITELOCK, BULSTRODE, 1605-1675
    - [Letter (copy) to Parliament reporting on the office of Clerk of the Market, 1655 Jan 12.], [n.d.] (Box 1)
  - EVERY, SIR SIMON
    - [Legal MS of 1651 debtors court case.], [n.d.] (Box 1)
  - TOMKINS, NATHANAEL, D.1681
    - [MS document promising to contimue certain annuities.], [n.d.] (Box 1)
      [late 17th century].
  - WINCHESTER, JOHN PAULET, 5TH MARQUESS OF, 1598-1675
    - "A Breviat of the Lord Sr Johns estate.", [n.d.] (Box 1)
      Contemporary MS copy, [1651].
      On the sequestering of his lands.
  - SYDENHAM FAMILY
    - "Mr Sydenham's tytle to the mannor of Brusford 24 March 1655.", [n.d.] (Box 1)
  - HARBOUL, SIR CHARLES, 1640?-1672?
    - ALS to unidentified lord, [1666 May 16] (Box 1)
  - LONG, SIR ROBERT, D. 1673
    - ALS to Heneage Finch, [1662 Sep 3] (Box 1)
  - GREAT BRITAIN. PARLIAMENT, 1640. HOUSE OF COMMONS.
    - Contemporary MS copies, [n.d.] (Box 1)
    - 10 documents of speeches and resolutions in the House of Commons, April 13-24. (Box 1)
  - [ANONYMOUS]
    - [Accounts, 1655 May and June] (Box 1)
      5 autograph MS of travel expenses
      incurred while conducting nobles
      under guard from prison.